How is it?
Good!
Excuse me?
Coming!
Coming...
It's been a while, Dai-chan.
Haruko...
What're you doing here all of a sudden?
Rin-chan!
Reina-chan?
What's going on, Reina-chan?
Are you going away somewhere?
Haruko...
Nope! We came to visit you!
Really?
Um...
Do you like sweet buns, Reina-chan?
What's a sweet bun?
It's a round and sweet snack.
Then I like it!
Rin, go get Reina-chan some barley tea.
Okay! Come on, Reina-chan!
We were just having snacks...
I want some, too!
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
It's really good!
Told you so!
This is the first time I've ever tried one!
Thanks.
It's so strange.
I've never been here before, but it feels so much like Granddad's house.
Are you going to tell me what's wrong?
You brought her school bag and stuff here on a Sunday...
Sorry...
The truth is that we've run away from home.
W-Wha...?!
They'll all be worried sick about you!
Why'd you do something like that?!
I-Is it that...?
Is it what?
I mean... Did something happen with your husb-
That's part of it.
Part of it?
Part of it!
Did something happen with his pare-
That's part of it, too!
I guess living with your husband's parents must be difficult, huh?
Perhaps it's just impossible for people to live together without tearing each other apart.
Scary!
I don't have any siblings, so we don't really have anywhere else to go...
Ah! That's the same maths textbook we use!
Really?
Is it okay if we stay here?
Y-You're going to have to tell me a bit more about the situation...
Let me see your other textbooks!
Sure! Um...
Have you told your parents?
Ah! Your Japanese textbook is different.
It's okay.
I left a note behind for my husband and his parents.
I want to see!
I didn't tell them where I was going, though.
Sure!
And I'll take Reina to school.
I haven't really thought about much beyond that,
and I haven't told my parents yet.
Haven't really thought about much?
But you brought your daughter here with you.
I had no other choice!
I had to get out of that house!
I couldn't bear another second there!
Guess it can't be helped.
For now, let's go pick up some things for dinner tonight.
Dai-chan...
I can't offer you much, but you can use the room on the right.
You're right! It really is different!
Thanks. It's a little heavy.
What the heck do you have stuffed in here?!
Reina's slippers and textbooks are in there, too, so...
I'm surprised you made it this far.
Dai-chan, I know what sort of stuff you get by on,
so tonight, I'll whip you up a real meal.
What's that supposed to mean?
Daikichi, can we go and look at the sweets?
Yeah. You can have one each.
Okay!
What sort of meat should we get?
Does it matter?
That one isn't good!
Take this one.
Maybe this one's not so good, either...
Ah, Daikichi-san! Hello!
Dai-chan, this ground beef and pork is really cheap!
Crap!
Ah! No! You've got it all wrong!
Her name's Haruko. She's my cousin on my mother's side.
Why does she need to know which side I'm on?
I see! Pleased to meet you!
My son is one of Rin-chan's classmates,
Damn. What am I saying? She didn't even ask...
and Daikichi-san is always helping me out...
I see! Then he'll be the same age as my daughter.
I don't even know why I'm making excuses, anyway.
Oh, really?
"You've got it all wrong!"? What the heck was I saying?!
I'm Reina.
She just started first grade.
I'm Kouki.
My!
Oh...
Yo, Kouki!
What sweets did you get?
Hey, Daikichi.
This!
Deluxe Big Nyan Gum!
I'm getting vegetable cakes!
I'm getting candy with a toy of Meow Meow Tumbles!
Are those really sweets?
She's really pretty, isn't she?
W-Well, I guess she's one of the prettier mothers I've met...
I wouldn't go about having a fling with her, though.
A-Are you some kind of moron?!
It's not like that at all!
Besides, she has her hands full taking care of Kouki on her own.
She wouldn't even have time for...
On her own?!
Idiot!
You've seen too many weird dramas!
She looks about two or three years older than us. What do you think?
Why should I care how old she is?!
So she's divorced, huh?
I don't really know...
It looks good!
I've never had this before!
I tried something a little different.
Usually, my mother-in-law has the last say on everything, so...
Mama, we should have this at home, too!
Well, then, let's eat!
Let's eat!
It's good!
Thank you, Rin-chan.
Hey, Reina. Hold your chopsticks properly.
Okay!
The floor's all creaky!
Reina! Take this towel!
Okay!
What's that?
A bra!
Hey, Reina! Don't pull on it like that!
Are they asleep?
Yeah, finally...
They were both pretty hyper.
I moved Rin-chan into your futon.
Thanks.
Thank you.
That's really good!
It's been too long since I've had alcohol!
Want something to eat, too?
I've been putting on weight recently, so I'll give it a pass.
It's just like I thought.
You mean I've really gained weight?!
No, no...
Just that we're definitely in our thirties now.
I'd take just being thirty now.
Once you get older, you just can't push yourself in the same way, you know?
You have to start taking care of yourself.
Although, it's not like my husband looks at me anymore, anyway.
I don't know who I'm trying to stay thin for.
Haruko...
What is it?
While you guys were in the bath, I called your house.
Huh?! Why?! Don't do weird things like that, Dai-chan!
It's not weird. They'll be worried about you.
All I told them was that you were both okay,
and that you'll be staying with me for a bit.
I didn't even tell them my address.
I already left them a letter!
So leave me alone!
I can't do that.
You can do what you want, but I'm worried about Reina.
Reina's with me, and she's holding up fine. What's wrong with that?
Even so, if you don't tell them where you are and that she's okay,
how the heck are they supposed to know she's safe?
I don't care about them.
You need to calm down a little.
Rin-chan...
Do you just want to cause your family trouble?
Come inside.
Okay.
That's my nose!
Papa and Mama are always fighting...
Even though they're married?
Yep. Even though they're married. I always pretend to just be asleep...
Let's hold hands.
Okay!
It tickles!
That's my cheek!
I... Every single day, I...
Since the day I got married, I've kept my feelings bottled up inside.
I have the right to cause them a bit of trouble, don't I?!
I'm sorry, Dai-chan...
That was a horrible thing to say...
No, it's fine...
I'm going to sleep.
Right.
Dai-chan...
Goodnight, Dai-chan.
Goodnight.
Rin-chan...
Good morning!
Good morning...
Rin-chan, are you making breakfast?
Ah, good morning Daikichi!
You're up early today, huh?
Yeah, I guess...
Hey, Dai-chan!
You have Rin-chan make you breakfast?!
D-Don't be stupid!
We always make meals together!
And when we're cooking with a flame, I-
Play nice!
Hey, you've got rice on your face.
Eat up quickly. We're taking the train to school today.
Rin-chan!
Who could that be at a time like this?
It's Kouki-kun.
We're here!
Just come in, already!
You're disturbing the neighbours!
Rin-chan, is your school far away?
You have to leave this early?
Nope!
Kouki-kun's mum is busy, so he comes here early.
G-Good morning.
Daikichi, did you get married?!
Of course not! She's my cousin!
Oh. That figures.
What's that supposed to mean?
Daikichi, you want to get married?
N-No, it's not like...
Mama, you'd rather be single, right?
What's "single"?
It means not being married.
Ah! I've heard of that! "Divorce", right?
I don't know what "divorce" is.
Hm... So your mum is married, but she wants to be single...
And Daikichi is single, but wants to be married?
Adults are so weird.
They really are.
Daikichi, can I have a rice ball?
You had breakfast before you came here, right?
Yeah.
Knock yourself out.
That one was supposed to be mine, though.
All right!
You didn't have breakfast?
You have a good heart, huh, Dai-chan?
Because I gave a kid a rice ball?
That's not what I mean.
Huh?
You're just as busy as her, right?
I guess you really have a thing for that pretty mother...
I-Id- Blockhead!
That again?!
I just thought that I could help out a little,
and Rin gets along well with the two of them.
But that's all.
I don't know the details,
but I'm sure Kouki and his mum have been through a lot.
It'd be rude of me to not respect that.
Single mothers really have it hard, don't they?
Huh?
Reina! I told you to hurry! We're going to be late!
Haruko...?
Good morning.
You have to keep where we're staying a secret.
Huh?! Why?
Just because. Do you understand?
Yep!
Good morning!
Reina-chan, did you come with your mum?
That's right!
We secretly ran away from home, so we came by train today!
What do you mean?
Wait!
Hey!
I told you to hold on tight.
I'm not getting you another one,
but it might be waiting for us when we get home, huh?
You might be right!
Hello!
Oh, you're working late tonight?
Yep! My husband's watching the kid.
Oh, is Yuu-kun well?
Sure is!
He's been so full of beans recently that I've barely been able to handle him.
It's nice that your husband helps out, though.
This is the first time he has!
And it's only because his business trip was rescheduled, so he's off.
Oh...
You just can't leave raising a kid to your husband, you know?
Hurry up! Reina-chan's waiting!
Right, right...
We're home, Reina-chan!
They fell asleep right away tonight.
Haruko, don't tell me that you're going to take things even further than this?
Oh, you mean a divorce or something?
Yeah, that.
No way. Not a chance.
Look at me, getting all worked up for nothing...
Well, I've thought about it plenty of times.
Actually, I think about it pretty much every day.
After all, when you start thinking about the man
you're married to as an enemy, things are already...
Apart from Reina, they're all strangers and enemies to me.
I think of our family being just the two of us,
but someone in my position simply can't afford to think like that.
I have Reina to think about, and then there's the question of how I'd make a living...
And with all the battles I'd have to fight to break away from my husband...
It seems like I'm better off just sticking with things the way they are.
I got married as soon as I joined a company.
At that age, all I thought about was becoming a good wife.
There's nothing else to it. No other way to protect Reina.
You know, I'm not even married,
and just keeping a family going is pretty difficult.
You do everything yourself, after all.
It's pretty amazing.
Nah, I haven't been able to do anything for her.
That's not how it is at all! Rin-chan looks like she's having lots of fun.
When she's cooking for you, for example...
And Kouki-kun and his mother are doing just fine on their own,
so Reina and I will be okay with just the two of us, too.
You keep saying it's just the two of you.
Don't you talk to your husband?
He's always stuck doing overtime, so we never talk.
So I'll do my best with just Reina.
Besides, I've put up with it for so many years already.
I'll be fine.
As long as I stop myself from feeling too much,
I can let pretty much anything go.
That's really unhealthy.
Quite the contrary!
If I didn't do it, I'd fall apart.
You've gotten really strong, Haruko.
Hm, I wonder.
To raise a kid, you need to be able to
call up these huge surges of strength,
especially when she's still a baby.
I don't really know what it's like with a baby, but...
And while I was doing that, I just sort of ended up like this.
I don't want to end up as some old lady.
I didn't want to be strong.
I wanted to just stay as a girl forever...
I'm sorry, Dai-chan.
Thank you.
We'll go home tomorrow.
Right...
What is marriage?
What does it mean to become a parent?
What's wrong?
It's your turn, Reina.
It really is!
"It really is" what?
Papa's car!
Papa's coming after he finishes work.
He wouldn't be here this early.
It's definitely Papa! I'm not wrong!
Reina, it's not him!
Papa!
I was worried about you, Reina.
I was worried about you, too!
Sorry.
Huh. So if he actually wants to get off
work at this time, he has no problem...
Hey, don't be like that.
It's pretty hard working at a company, too, you know.
Stupid Hideyuki-san...
I'm so sorry.
Haruko's caused you so much trouble.
Ah, no, it really wasn't a...
I'm wearing the wrong clothes for this!
Thank you so much, Dai-chan.
Papa could at least carry our bags, couldn't he?
He's always so inconsiderate.
Yeah! "Inconsridat"!
You can come back any time you feel like it.
No, I can't cause you any more trouble.
No, that's not what I mean.
Rin is always going on about how much she wants to see Reina-chan.
Thank you... Dai-chan...
Mama! Mama!
Then can we come this Sunday?!
H-Hey, Reina!
Haruko as a child, always in tears...
And Haruko last night, whispering
that she wanted to be a girl forever...
Well, then...
Next time you come, pack a little lighter.
My arms hurt just looking at that bag.
No can do.
Girls have an awful lot of things to carry, you know.
This is nothing.
Bye bye!
I'll see you off!
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
How about this?
Yeah!
Ah, but maybe this one would suit you better...
What do you think?
Can I try this one on, too?
Go ahead!
I'm thirsty!
Ah, she just has to try it on, so...
Oh! Isn't this one lovely?
Um... Kouki and I are going to go for a little walk.
Okay!
Look! It really suits you!
Let's go.
You're so cute, Rin-chan!
Good?
It tastes like summer!
Sure does!